# NOMINATION FORM: APPLICABLE TO ALL LOCAL MUNICIPALITIES

#### 2. NOMINATOR'S INFORMATION:

2.1. NAME OF MUNICIPALITY	Matjhabeng Local Municipality.		
2.2. NOMINATOR	Anastasia Hanana (Insert name and surname of the nominator)		
2.3. IDENTITY NUMBER		8011160077086	
2.4. CONTACT NUMBER OF NOMINATOR	082 370 5447		
2.5. SIGNATURE OF NOMINATOR	abbur	2017/05/19 DATE	
(This signature implies tha	t the nominator knows the nominee	and can testify to the abilities of the nominee)	

#### 3. NOMINEE'S INFORMATION:

3.1. I, THE NOMINATOR HEREBY NOMINATE:	Please ens	*****		names and of Name a		of the nominee) the as this name will be	e used in official
3.2. DISCIPLINE OF NOMINEE (Mark with X)	Town and Regional	Land surveyor	Building Inspector	Environment al Expert	Agriculturalis t	Engineer (Please specify)	Other (Please specify)

3.3. GENDER (Mark with X):	Malé	Female
3.4. IDENTITY NUMBER OF NOMINEE:	900 708 58	63 OB
3.5. RESIDENTIAL ADDRESS OF NOMINEE:	25 Appensport	Westclere, Bleen firter, 9301
3.6. POSTAL ADDRESS OF NOMINEE		,
3.7. CONTACT NUMBE OF NOMINEE:	0825147219	,
3.8. SIGNATURE OF NOMINEE:	13. Mga	30/05/2017 DATE
This signature implies that the nor Accepts this nomination Agrees to abide by the		al and Local government.

#### APPOINTMENT OF MEMBERS TO THE MUNICIPAL PLANNING TRIBUNAL INVITATION FOR NOMINATIONS

Interested persons are invited in terms of section 35(1) of SPLUMA to nominate persons representing the following disciplines (Town and Regional Planner, Building Inspector, Environmental Expert, Agriculturalist, Engineer or any other person who has the knowledge of and interest in town planning) to serve on the Municipal Planning Tribunal. The members of the Tribunal shall hold office for a period of five years (5) years.

#### **Function of the Municipal Planning Tribunal**

To consider and formulate the decisions regarding all land development applications in the local municipality

#### **Submissions of Nominations**

Nominations must be submitted with information pertaining to name, residential and postal address, Curriculum Vitae and telephone number(s)

#### 1. CLOSING DATE AND SUBMISSION:

The closing date for submission of the nomination is 31 May 2017

#### 1.1. Each nomination must be accompanied by the following documents:

- A copy of the nominee's ID document; and
- Latest CV of the nominee.
- 1.1.1. Nominations must reach the following address on or before **end of business on the 31 May 2017** in order for nominations to be distributed to the relevant local municipalities.

Mr Boipelo Molelekoa Senior Chief Town Planner – Spatial Planning Matjhabeng Local Municipality 1 Reinet Street Welkom 9460

Tel: (057) 916 4011 Fax: 086 548 3919

Email: Boipelo.Molelekoa@matjhabeng.co.za

# Kgosi Simphiwe Mocwagae

41 Memveille Reveille Crescent Generaal De Wet Bloemfontein 9301

Cell number: +27(0) 82 514 7219

Email: mocwagaeks@gmail.com /

mocwagaeks@ufs.ac.za

Date of birth : 08 July 1990

Gender : Male

Marital Status : Single

Nationality : South African

Driver's License : Code B

### **Educational Qualifications**

## Secondary Education

☐ Matriculated at Witteberg High School in 2007

#### Subjects:

Mathematics; Afrikaans 2<sup>nd</sup> Language; English 1<sup>st</sup> Language; seSotho 3<sup>rd</sup> Language; Biology; Physical Science; Technical Drawings; Computer Studies

#### Tertiary Education

1. Philosophiae Doctor (Ph.D.) - University of the Free State (UFS) (2016 – to date)

Title: A Tale of Three Dams: Exploring QwaQwa Water Crisis for Effective Planning in Post-Democratic South Africa.

2. Masters in Urban and Regional Planning – UFS (2014 – 2015)

#### **Course Modules:**

Integrated Development Planning; Geographical Information Systems for Planners; Extended Research Essay; Research Methodologies for Planners; Applied Regional Planning Project; Urban Research Project; Planning Management; Dissertation Proposal in Urban and Regional Planning; Professional Planning Practice

**Research Title:** The viability of a corridor development to maximise the economic opportunities in the region: The case of the N8-road from Bloemfontein and Maseru

3. Baccalaureus of Spatial Planning (Hons) – UFS (2013)

#### **Course Modules:**

Anthropology for Planners; Research in Regional Planning Theory; Housing for Planners; Environmental Planning; Planning Theory; Applied Economic Research for Planners; Computer use for Planners; Urban Planning Practice; Urban Development Theory

Baccalaureus Scientae Information Technology – UFS (2008 – 2012) Course
 Modules:

Computer Hardware; Computer Literacy; Calculus; Physical Science; Webdesign; Web-development; Marketing; C# Programming; Human Resource Management; Strategic Management; Accounting; Management Accounting; Database Management Systems; Computer Networks; Financial Management; Internet Marketing; Entrepreneurship; Soil Science; Graphic Interface Design

# **Employment**

Position	Institution	Period
1. Junior Lecturer	UFS	January 2015 – to date
2. Committee Member	SAPI	March 2015 – to date
3. Technical Assistant	UFS	November 2014 – December 2014
4. Fieldworker	TGPA	November 2014 – April 2015
5. Research Assistant	UFS	February 2014 – October 2014
6. Student Assistant	UFS	August 2012 – January 2014
7. Trustee and Committee member	Genesis ARK	February 2012 – May 2016
8. Peer Educator / Tutor	UFS	July 2009 – November 2012
9. Supervisor, 2010 FIFA World Cup	Inn-Staff	June 2010 – July 2010
10. Residence Committee (RC) RAG	UFS	May 2009 – April 2010
11. Project Leader KOVSCOM 2008	UFS	September 2008 – August 2009

# **Work Experience**

1. Junior Lecturer – Department of Urban and Regional Planning, UFS:

I have the responsibilities of teaching and conducting research in that are Urban and Regional Planning related, and also offer students with guidance with the modules I teach.

I am actively involved in teaching the following modules:

- **GAD404: Planning and Transformation** A fourth year Construction Management module that deals with nature of planning and transformation in South Africa pre-apartheid through to democracy.
- ATB622 and URSC6814 / 6824: Research in Socio-Cultural Aspects in Planning – It's an honours module to equip students with skills and the knowledge of conducting research that relates to culture and tradition in the field of Urban and Regional Planning.
- URBP6808: Basic Practice in Urban and Regional Planning This module equips honours students with the skills and knowledge that they can apply in the spatial context.
- URRP7906: Applied Regional Planning Project A master's module that deals with regional planning issues that are resolved through research and offering proposals to resolve these.
- URPP7924: Professional Planning Practice The module equips master's students with the skills and knowledge of the Urban and Reginal Planning in both the private and public, and offers guidance in career planning.

To date I have successfully co-supervised one Masters student and have two article pending for publication.

2. Committee Member – South African Planning Institute (SAPI), Free State Region:

Responsibities and duties are representing the UFS in SAPI in order to serve the interests of the students and the university.

3. Technical Assistant – Department of Computer Science and Informatics:

As a Technical Assistant for the Department of Computer Science and Informatics I maintained, upgraded and monitored both computer hardware and software with the help of network based applications for computers used for the Computer Literacy module at the Main and South Campuses of the UFS.

#### 4. Fieldwork - Tshidi Gudlhuza Planners & Associates (TGPA):

Responsibilities included collection of data for a housing policy for the Mangaung Metropolitan Municipality, and report writing.

#### 5. Research Assistant - Department of Urban and Regional Planning:

My responsibilities are to assist all the entire academic staff of the department with research needs, which range from fieldwork, acquisition of academic literature and general administration.

#### 6. Student Assistant – Provisioning, UFS:

My responsibilities were to deliver stationary and groceries to the respective departments at the UFS main and South Campus. Just as any other job I had to meet targets for each and every day that I had stock to deliver.

#### 7. Trustee and Chairperson – Genesis ARK:

I am a part of a group of young individuals that have taken the responsibility of uplifting South Africa and the world at large into a nation as envision by great of the likes of Nelson Mandela and mother Theresa. As a Trustee of Genesis ARK, I am responsible for overseeing the media and marketing portfolio. My responsibility is therefore to take Genesis ARK to greater heights and serve more and more of my people in the global sphere.

#### 8. Supervisor - 2010 FIFA World Cup:

My responsibilities as the supervisor for the food and beverage department, were to ensure that staff members were punctual and were well behaved while on duty, and that the service we were providing was of quality, while also address problems and conflict among staff members.

#### 9. Peer Educator / Tutor – UFS:

To help improve the understanding and knowledge of students in terms of basic computer literacy. I had to help the lecturer's teaches form into its practical form.

#### 10. RC RAG - UFS:

My responsibilities were to lead the residence in an initiative for of fundraising money for charity along with 21 other residences, promote social cohesion among residence members and create a credible record for the residence.

#### 11. Project Leader KOVSCOM 2008 – UFS:

Helping with the distribution of the funds raised through KOVSIE RAG and also being involved in attending the social responsibility that one has an individual of helping out those who are less fortunate than myself.

#### **Achievements**

I have spent many years at the UFS, occupying posts in leadership, support and academic respectively. Outside the UFS I have been a supervisor and chairperson. This has contributed to having a variety of skills in different fields.

In leadership I managed to be the youngest person to ever occupy a position for both project leading and RC RAG at House Khayalami at the UFS due to my commitment and contribution. As project leader I had to help the UFS and my residence distribute charity funds through planned projects in the Mangaung Township. As the RC RAG I attended workshops presented by the UFS in partnership with iGubu for effective and efficient student leadership.

For support at the Department of Provisioning (UFS) I was the first student to work without a partner for a period of a year and a half. I also worked seven hours a day while being a full-time student during my Baccalaureus Scientae Information Technology and Baccalaureus (Hons) of Spatial Planning studies. I had to put in the hours to make sure that I completed by studies on both the undergraduate and postgraduate levels.

In my academic capacity I gathered most of my experience in tutoring computer literacy for a period of three years. I was a part of the New Academic Tutorial Programme (NATP) in 2009 where we had to teach novice computer users, from the Mangaung Township in Bloemfontein, to learn basic computer skills in typing and then certify those that successfully complete the programme. Nine people out of 10 completed the course successfully. Another part of the NATP included giving revision classes to first year computer literacy students at the UFS. I continued tutoring students for their practical's from 2010 to 2012. In 2014 I joined the Department of URP at the UFS where I assisted academic staff with collecting research papers, marking and general administration work. Besides my designated duties I also managed to work with the department staff and head the department get its first clothing gear.

In 2010 Inn-Staff offered me the opportunity to be a supervisor at the 2010 FIFA World Cup in Bloemfontein. The world cup was a success, I'd like to consider it as one of my greatest achievements, because I and my team were a part of the people that made it a success. I learned to resolve conflict among staff members and reach the goals and

targets that my employer aimed for. I was 20 years old at the time and was in charge of a group that ranged from 20 to 35 years of age.

I am currently a trustee and chairperson of Genesis ARK that is a registered NPO. Genesis ARK is a charity organisation that aims to uplift communities in South Africa and aiming to uplift the world at large in future. Genesis ARK was established in 2009 and I was invited to join in 2012 due to my previous experience in charity work in House Khayalami (UFS). I can successfully say that Genesis ARK has positively impacted the lives of over 1000 people since its establishment.

#### Other skills

Language Proficiency:	Speak	Read	Write
Afrikaans	Moderate	Moderate	Moderate
English	Good	Good	Good
seSotho	Good	Moderate	Moderate

Computer literacy: I am an advanced computer user, with more than 10 years'

experience of computer literacy. Attached to this document are supporting documents of literacy and contributions that I have for

tutoring students and the community in Bloemfontein.

Communication: I work very well in large groups as I Have led many projects that

are mentioned above, and I am also a committed and goal driven

individual.

Other: Organizing skills. I've been actively involved with helping out and

leading projects of organizing events which were a huge success.

# Workshops attended

Supplemental Instruction(SI), (UFS), October 2009

Peer learning facilitation

Leadership Skills: Planning, (UFS), October 2009

Projects and Running Projects

Leadership Skills: Group, (UFS) October 2009

Dynamics, Diversity and Support

Courageous Student, (UFS)

October 2009

Leadership in Residences (RC Training)

South African Planning Institute (SAPI),

Skills Programme

August 2013

Honours Mentorship Programme, (UFS) Ju

July 2014 - October 2014

Conference for Planning Students and

Young Graduates, University of

Johannesburg

December 2014

# **Professional Membership**

- SAPI Urban and Regional Planning Associate, Member no. 12291, November 2013 – to date
- South African Council for Planners (SACPLAN), C/7854/2016

#### Referees:

1. Dr. Maléne Campbell

Department of Urban and Regional Planning: Head of Department

Tel: +27(0)51 401 3575

Email: <a href="mailto:campbemm@ufs.ac.za">campbemm@ufs.ac.za</a>

2. Mr. Sam Moleko

Phatsoane Henny Attorneys: Director - Commercial Services

Cell: +27(0)72 460 3347 Email: sam@phinc.co.za

3. Mr. Dumisa Dlamini

Tshidi Gudlhuza Planners & Associates: Technical Director

Cell: +27(0)76 390 8409 Email: <u>dumisad@gmail.com</u> BK SERTIFISEER DAT HIERDIE DOKUMENT IN WARE AFDRUK AFKSRIF, IS VAN DK SCH I MIDDER DAT MERAVE DERDINGEN I IN WARE AFUNDY MEKSKIFT IS VAN OORSPRONKLIKE DOKUMENT LAF AGULTY ME WAARNEMING VOORGELE IS SERTIFISEER VERDER DAT VOLGENS HY L'MARNEMINGS DAAF ME NIVYST OF VERANDERING OP DIE OORSPRONKLIKE DOKUMENT AANGEBRING IS NIE

I CERTIFY THAT THIS DOCUMENT IS A TRUE REPRODUCTION COPY: OF THE ORIGINAL DOCUMENT WHICH THAT HAVE REPRODUCTION COPYLOF THE ORIGINAL DOCUMENT WHICH THAT HAVE NOTICE TO ME FOR AUTHENTICATION FURTHER CERTIFY THAT FROM LIY CERTIFY ATTOM AN AMENOMENT OR H

CHANGE WAS NOT MADE TO THE ORIGINAL DOCUMENT

MOKETOT

ENING / SIGNATURE

RANG RAN

KOMMISSARIS VAN EDE / COMMISSIONER OF CATE UNIVERSITEIT VAN DIE VRYSTAAT UNIVERSITY OF THE EST NELSON MANDELARYLAAN DRIVE BLOEMFONTEIN 9300

BESKERMINGSDIENSTE UNIVERSITEIT VAN DIE VRYSTAAT

17 -03- 2017

PROTECTION SERVICES UNIVERSITY OF THE FREE STATE BLOEMFONTEIN

#### GEREGISTREERDE WOON EN POSADRES

- 1. Bewaar die bewys van u GEREGISTREERDE WOON EN POSADRES in hierdie sakkie.
- 2. Indien u van adres verander het, of indien besonderhede van u huidige adres, bv. straanaam en/of -nommer, ens. verander het moet die vorm KENNISGEWING VAN ADRESVERANDERING, wat in die sakkte agter in die dentiteitsdokument is; gebruik word om die verandering aan te meid en moet dit ingedien word by of gepos word aan die naaste streek-ridstrikkantoor van die DEPARTEMENT VAN BINNELANDSE SAKE.

#### REGISTERED RESIDENTIAL AND POSTAL ADDRESS

- 1. Keep the proof of your REGISTERED RESIDENTIAL AND POSTAL ADDRESS in this pocket.
- 2. If you have changed your address, or, if particulars of your present address, e.g. name of siteel and/or street number, etc., have been changed, the NOTICE OF CHANGE OF ADDRESS form in the pocket at the back of the identity document must be used to report the change and it must be handed in at or posted to the nearest regional district office of the DEPARTMENT OF HOME AFFAIRS.

# I.D.No. 900708 5863 08 8

MOCWAGAE

VOORNAME/FORENAMES KGOSI SIMPHIWE

GEBOORTEDISTRIK OF-LAND/ DISTRICT OR COUNTRY OF BIRTH

SOUTH AFRICA

GEBOORTEDATUM/ DATE OF BIRTH

1990-07-08

DATUM UITGEREIK DATE ISSUED

2006-02-10

UITGEREIK OP GESAG VAN DIE DIREKTEUR-GENERAAL: BINNELANDSE SAKE

ISSUED BY AUTHORITY OF THE DIRECTOR-GENERAL: HOME AFFAIRS

